Then, the third measure of
第三种相似性衡量方法是
similarity that we are going to look at is called Kendall's tau.
Kendall's tau 相关系数
You can see again that this uses rank data but then there's a sign.
同样使用了排名数据 但是这里有个 sign
So, the sign is either a positive or a negative.
sign 为正或为负
So, this is basically saying,
这个公式表示
if two things are both positive,
如果两项都为正
then this will become a positive one.
那么这个将为 1
Whereas, if two things are both negative,
如果两个都为负
then that's still a positive one.
那么这个依然是 1
If two things are pointing in opposite directions,
如果两项的方向相反
then it's like a hit against Kendall's tau,
那么就好像与 Kendall's tau 对立
and that x and y are moving in relationship to one another.
x 和 y 的移动方式相互关联
So, if they're both positive or both negative,
如果都为正或都为负
then things are moving in the same direction, they're more similar.
则朝着相同的方向移动 它们更相似
Whereas if one's positive and one's negative,
如果一个为正 另一个为负
then they're moving in different directions,
则朝着不同的方向移动
and therefore they should be considered less similar.
所以二者关系不太相似
That idea that's going into Kendall's tau.
这就是 Kendall's tau 相关系数的含义
So, we can calculate that.
我们来看看计算方法
Again, I'm going to grab some of the pieces.
再看看这些变量
So, we're going to grab n which is just the length,
n 表示长度
and we're again using these ranked versions of things.
同样使用已排名版本
So, we're going to
像这样
pull the ranked versions like this,
提取已排名版本
and then we also want this part here.
还需要这部分
So, n is just going to be though length,
n 等于长度
and x and y should be the same length.
x 和 y 应该长度相同
So, it doesn't really matter which one you put the length of.
所以用谁的长度都一样
Then essentially, what I want to do do is I want to
接下来
create something where I'm keeping track of this order.
我将跟踪这个顺序
So, if i is less than j,
如果 i 大于 j
then we're going to take the difference between these things,
那么我们将计算这些差值
but if it's not, then we don't take the sum.
如果 i 不大于 j 则不求和
So, this is a little tricky here.
这里有点难
What I'm going to do is,
我将创建 sum_vals
I'm going to create the sum values thing where I'm going to keep track of all my sums.
用于跟踪所有的和
I'm going to iterate through the x values and y values together.
我将同时遍历 x 值和 y 值
I'm going to look at the index up them.
查看它们的索引
A nice way to be able to look at the index of anything is to use enumerate,
通过 enumerate() 可以轻松地查看索引
and the nice thing to keep x and y together is to zip them.
使用 zip() 可以将 x 和 y 放到一起
So, basically, what this is doing is it slips them together.
这部分将它们 zip 到一起
So, it's putting those two vectors together as one thing,
将这两个向量组合到一起
and then enumerate is going to pull out which index we're on.
然后 enumerate() 将提取我们所在的索引
Then, we can do basically the same thing again.
然后执行相同的步骤
So, this i is the same as this i here,
这个 i 与这个 i 一样
and then the j is the same as this j up here.
这个 j 与这个 j 一样
So, we're looking at the i iteration,
我们查看的是第 i 次迭代
we're subtracting the j iteration,
减去第 j 次迭代
as long as i is less than j.
前提是 i 小于 j
So, that's what we're keeping track up here.
这就是我们要跟踪的内容
So, here's i and j,
这是 i 和 j
and then yi and yj.
这是 yi 和 yj
I'm going to change this to j and j.
将这里改成 j 和 j
So, now, my syntax and the code actually lines up really nicely with the math.
现在我的代码语法与数学公式保持一致了
Basically, I'm going to say,
原理是
if i is less than j,
如果 i 小于 j
then what I want to do is I want to add to my sum values,
则与 sum_vals 相加
and there's actually a really nice way to do this in NumPy which is called np sign.
NumPy 中有一个很方便的函数可以完成此操作 叫做 np.sign
So, there's an np sign function.
在这里使用 np.sign 函数
We're just going to take the difference between those two things and add them in.
对这两项求差值 然后相加
So, x i minus x j.
x_i - x_j
So, we're going to take x i minus x j,
输入 x_i - x_j
and we're going to multiply that by the sine of y i minus y j.
乘以 sign(y_i - y_j)
So, y minus y j,
y_i - y_j
there should be a minus sign here.
这里应该是减号
So, when multiply those things together,
将它们相乘
that's going to give me the sum values.
得出 sum_vals
Once we sum through all of those,
对所有这些求和后
we want to do this part out here.
再完成这部分
So then, the last part that we need to do is just this part here.
最后完成这一部分
So, take two times this sum values thing that we get back,
使这里算出的 sum_vals 乘以 2
and then divide it pi n times n minus one,
然后除以 n(n-1)
two times the sum values,
sum_vals 乘以 2
It looks like that passes all the tests.
看来通过了所有测试
So, then we can use our function to define these things.
下面根据此函数回答这些问题
So, for all columns, we'll play data do
对于 play_data 的所有列
Spearman's and Kendall's tau match and then similarly for Spearman versus Pearson,
斯皮尔曼系数和 Kendall's tau 系数匹配吗？然后是斯皮尔曼系数与皮尔逊系数
and Pearson vs Kendall,
还有皮尔逊系数与 Kendall 系数
and all, let you do that part.
由你来回答这些问题吧
Okay. So, next, we are going to look at different distance functions.
Ok接下来我们将学习不同的距离函数
These are actually pretty simple to compute,
这些方法很好计算
especially considering what we just did.
尤其是刚刚已经介绍了三个相关系数的计算方法
So, I think I'll just leave this for you.
所以由你自己来完成吧